Hello, I'm super excited to start this course with you, but as always, before we do, we need to
see where we're starting and where we're ending up so we have a clear path to succeeding.
So let's see what this course will look like for you.
Were first going to start off with creating our hacking lab.
Now, don't worry whether you're on Windows, Mac or Linux, you're going to be able to follow because
what we'll do is use something called a virtual machine to install CALEIGH Linux, which is often used
with ethical hacking onto our machine so that we can simulate and create our hacking environment.
Don't worry, all the tools we're going to use is free and you're going to be able to set up your computer
in a way to follow the rest of the course.
And you're also going to have a professional setup.
We're also going to cover some basics on hacking, some fundamentals and principles that's going to
set us up for success later on in the course.
Then we have an optional part for those that really want to get into programming as well and possibly
programming some of our projects later on in the course, we're going to teach you Python from scratch
or if you know Python already as a refresher so that you can also learn an extra pair of skill set for
some harder projects that we have in the course.
Then we get into the fun part and the first step we're going to dive into after we have our hacking
lab and some of our programming skills.
Sharp is reconnaissance.
Here is where we learn what we call footprinting, or in other words, information gathering once we
choose our target.
Our first task is to gain as much information about the target as possible.
We're going to talk about IP addresses, about the Who is Tooele, the Web Stiltskin, finding usernames,
building an email scraper tool and other tools available to us to gather as much information as possible.
From there we go into Skåne and this is where things get real.
In this section, we gather information on some of the technical information that we can acquire from
a target.
For example, if they have open ports, if they have a firewall, what software they're running on these
ports and if they have any outdated operating systems.
And don't worry, if you don't know what any of this means, we take you from scratch and you're going
to learn it all.
Here is where we learn about TCP UDP using the powerful and map tool, different types of scans that
we can do, how to work with firewalls, using decoys and packet fragmentation.
And we're also going to build a port scanner project in the section.
From there we go into vulnerability analysis.
In this section we use the information that we gathered from the previous sections and with this information
that we tried to determine whether there is a known vulnerability that we can take advantage of.
We're going to use different sorts of tools to learn about our target system and where their weaknesses
are.
We're actually going to work on a Windows seven machine that has a vulnerability and show how we can
break into it and how we can use that to our advantage then.
Well, this is the exciting part.
This is the big part of the course.
This is where we attack and gain access to the target machines.
And throughout this session, we'll be covering many different vulnerabilities and different targets.
We perform different sorts of attacks on virtual machines and cover a very important tool of an ethical
hacker.
That is that Métis point framework.
The goal of exploitation is to get on a target machine.
So this means we must drop a payload on that target machine so we can use it to navigate through their
systems, look through their files, execute anything we want, even delete anything we want without
the target.
Knowing anything about it.
We'll learn to create our own viruses and Trojans that we can deliver to the target, whether through
an email or through a USB.
This is a big section and we're going to dive into the weeds, try out these techniques and learn how
to defend against them.
After that, we have what we call the post exploitation.
This, as the name suggests, is what we do after we exploit a target.
Since we're on that machine, we can do many things depending on what we want to get out from it at
the end after we do all the things we wanted by exploiting the target, we want to make sure we cover
our tracks by deleting any event logs or deleting any evidence that we were ever on that machine.
We're going to learn lots of things here, such as creating persistence on a target machine and even
creating a backdoor in one of our projects.
We then get into a very important part that a lot of you might find very, very interesting, and that
is website penetration testing.
This is a big topic for an ethical hacker.
And in this section, we're mainly targeting websites and their bugs and vulnerabilities.
These vulnerabilities can be anything from misconfiguration, askew, all injections, information disclosures,
command ejections.
Site scripting attacks, and we're also going to quote our own and create our own project to a login
brute force script and also a directory discovery tool.
Again, in this section, you're going to learn how to use these techniques and therefore defend against
them on your own website or a client's Web site.
Then we get into something that you have to know as an ethical hacker.
It's the man in the middle attack.
This is an attack that is used inside a network.
And this allows us to sniff any unencrypted data and see it in plain text so we could use this technique
to see passwords for some websites.
And we're going to cover some of the main tools that hackers use when doing a man in the middle attack.
We then have a bonus section on wi fi and wireless cracking.
This is the section where we want to gain access to a network by cracking its wireless password.
And we're going to talk about things like air crack, password cracking and cat password cracking and
show you how you might use this and how attackers might use this on your wireless network.
Now, we got lots to cover, but I also want to talk about the best bar right here, our online private
community of over 300000 students.
We have people chatting here every day helping each other out to finish the course, doing challenges
together and talking about the latest and greatest in technology.
This is an optional resource for you to use so you can have back and forth conversation with other students
and myself.
So you feel like you're part of a real classroom.
But you know what?
Enough talk.
I know you're getting excited.
I am, too.
So let's get started and let's learn ethical hacking.